

### ALINA BABER

### SKILLS

	Expert	Intermediate  Blockchain, Quantum Computing	
Technology	Al & Data Sciences, IoT Arduino Microcontroller,		
	programming		
Languages	Python, R, C#, C++, C, Kotlin, JAVA, JAVA Script, HTML5, CSS3, PHP	React, React native, flutter	
Platforms	Flask, Django, React, ASP.NET, WPF,WFP, MVC, Shiny R, MatLab, Visual Studio, Unity, Android Studio	Node.js	
Database	MySQL,MSSQL,ORACLE	MongoDB,Firebase	
Software	Pycharm ,PLS, IBM SPSS, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, CISCO, Visual Studio, MICROS RES POS,MS office.	Flash, Aftereffects, Premiere	
Serversite	Xampp, Asp.net,	Docker, Kubernetes	

#### EXPERIENCE

### Founder, AI & Robotics Scientist | Alphatron Technologies (Private) Limited | Feb 2015-Present

Al Software, web/mobile/Integrated systems & IoT development, research and technical writing, graphic designing and student project supervisory and consultancy.

### Co-Founder, CTO, AI & Robotics Scientist | KissanTech | Jan 2020-Present

Al Software, web/mobile/Integrated systems & IoT development, research and technical writing, graphic designing and student project supervisory and consultancy.

### Jr System Engineer | Business Vision 2000 | Sept 2014-Jan 2015

MICROS RES POS Configuration, Installation,
Database Design and Support (Call, Remotely, Visit).
Reason of leaving: Health Issues.

### Internee | PTCL (Pakistan Internet Exchange) | Jul 2014-Jan 2015

study and observation and monitoring of internet network, routers, configuration of routers switches etc.

#### INTRODUCTION

I'm AI & Robotics Scientist Founder, CEO of Alphatron Technologies (Private) Limited my startup and Cofounder AND CTO to Kissan Tech. who can think "Out of the box", have strong experience in areas of natural interfaces, Cognitive Sciences and Robotics/Autonomous application of AI in research, analysis, design and development of innovative ideas, distributed & integrated and IoT based systems design & architecture etc. No platform limits.





alinababer46@gmail.co m, alinababer@live.com

<u>Skype</u>





<u>LinkedIn URL</u>

Twitter handle

Links to Other Online Properties:

https://www.facebook.com/Alina.Baber http://www.slideshare.net/AlinaBaber

Contact/WhatsApp: +923314989588, +923413989588.

### ACHIEVEMENTS

External Speaker & Mentor at Karachi.Al community

External Speaker & Mentor at Usman Institute of Technology CS Dept.

News article publication about final Year project "E-Voting System through Iris Recognition" in THE EXPRESS TRIBUNE,

### EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science | Oct 2010 - Aug 2014 | Hamdard University (UIT) | Karachi

CGPA 3.13.

Intermediate | Science General (CS) | Sept 2008 – Mar 2010 | Govt College for Women Nazimabad | Karachi

2nd Division Grade: C.

Matriculation | Science (CS) | Sept 2006 – Mar 2008 | Al Mumtaz Islamic School | Karachi

1st Division Grade: A.

### COOREPERATE SECTOR PROJECTS

Projec	Client	Period	Platform	Role
Official	Energy	15 Jan	Laravel	Project
Website	Department of	2020-		Head
	Sindh	30 June		
		2030		
Official	Sindh	15 Jan	WordPress	Developer
Website	Transmission	2020-		
	and Dispatch	30 June		
	Company	2030		
Energy	Sindh	15 Nov	Unity3D	Project
Мар	Transmission	2019-		Head
Applica	and Dispatch	Present		
tion	Company			

### STARTUP PRODUCTS

Kissan Tech Smart farming | Product | Co-Founder, Main Developer | React, Nod.js, Python, IOT | 10 Nov 2019 – Present | Kissan Tech (Own) | Karachi

It's My startup with Mr. Rashid Mehmood Bhatti and Mr Ali, to smart farming by geo mapping, climate-based pest and disease forecast and crop and food quality recognition and farm management systems, to digitalize Agriculture sector with online consultancy, ecommerce platform, Ai based smart farming products, Saas Based systems.

Abirah virtual Assistant and Smart homes | Product |
Co-Founder, Main Developer | React, Nod.js,
Python, IOT | 10 Nov 2019 – Present | Alphatron
Technologies (Own) | Karachi

It's My startup product, of Smart homes with our own AI based virtual assistant according to our local market configurations and language with smart home managements and monitoring.

News Headline "E-Voting System through Iris Recognition" in Samaa TV, Dawn news, Dunia News and Jaag TV.

EXTRA CURRICULAR
ACTIVITES OR
VOLUNTORY
EXPERIENCE

Speaker of Reinforcement Learning | 29th Sept 2018 | National Incubator Center, NED University | Karachi

Introduction to Reinforcement Learning and its applications in Finance Industry at Karachi Al Community Meetup

Speaker of Artificial Intelligence | 31th Oct 2018 | UIT | Karachi

Introduction to the AI trend and its Market and jobs

Voluntary Experience | Sept 2006 – Mar 2008 | UIT | Karachi

Participation, Volunteering and Event Organizing | Comnet, Techno wave.

Extra-Curricular Activates | Feb 2015 – Present | Iridium Films Studio | Karachi

Script Writing, Poet, Song writer Art Direction, Story boarding and Concepts.

#### **Hobbies | Sports**

Reading, Novel Writing, Poetry song Writing, Painting, Sketching, Travelling, exercising, playing games & Music.

#### Out of Field Work | Art and Music

Project Head, Script Writing, Client dealing of My Brothers projects related to music and video production and post, animation and graphic designing

### AI & DATA SCIENCE RESEARCH PROJECTS

Reinforcement Learning, Fuzzy logics and Neural Network based self-tuned PID Controller for Autonomous Underwater Vehicle | Research Project | Computer Programmer | MATLAB | Jan 2018 – Nov 2019 | Jiangsu University of Science and Technology | China

based on Back propagation is to automatically tune the gains of a PID controller. The optimal set of gains is computed online with less computational effort by using desired and actual state variables Through Fuzzy logics, Neural Network and Reinforcement Learning algorithm. the optimal PID controller is designed for the for-docking tracking for autonomous underwater vehicle. For orientational motion of chaser and target missions and docks, self-tuned PID controller would be implemented. I was working with Phd student Aleena Akhter at Zhengzhou Univeristy, China.

Apt Attack Anomaly Analysis and Detection with Optimized Random forest Ensemble Learning Model | Research Project | Computer Programmer | Python | Jan 2018 – Nov 2019 | Client | Karachi

based on optimized ensemble learning models to analyze the Apt attack anomaly detection. I'm working with Phd student Mr.Safdar at private university of Karachi Pakistan

Distant Speech Analysis and Recognition | Research Project | Computer Programmer | Mat Lab | Oct 2016 - May 2017 | NED University | Karachi

Speech Recogntion by deep learning LSTM, CNN, ENSEMBLE LEARNING for distant and noisy speech recognition, I have worked with Mr Danish Khan who is completing his Phd at Ned University.

Stock Market Analysis | Module | Developer | R | 15 October 2020 – 1 November 2020 | for client | Germany

Stock market stock ranking and analysis.

Covid19 Updates and Forecast Web application | Module | Developer | R | 1 October 2020 – 1 15 October 2020 | for client | Australia

Covid19 updates by john Hopkin live data with its geo mapping and forecast.

### LANGUAGES

Language | Proficiency | Type
English | Full Professional | Official
Urdu | Native | National Tongue
Punjabi | Native | Mother Tongue

**Sindhi** | Limited Working | Regional **Spanish** | Limited Working | Interest

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name: **BABER HUSSAIN**Date of Birth: **02-07-1992**Place of Birth: **Karachi, Pakistan** 

Gender: Female
Religion: Islam
Nationality: Pakistani
Marital Status: Single
CNIC no: 42401-0579792-0
Passport no: AX3027921
Passport Validity: 03 May 2021

Postal Code: **75890** 

Address: A-177 Sec-1 Haji Fazal Town, Sultanabad , New Karachi- Orangi Link Road,Near Naya Nazimabad, Manghophir,Karachi, Pakistan

#### CONTACT

Outlook: alinababer@live.com

Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/">https://www.facebook.com/</a>

<u>Alina.Baber</u>

Gmail: alinababer46@gmail.com

Twitter: @AlinaBaber046
Instagram: @alinababer
Skype: alina.baber046
WhatsApp: +923314989588

Other Contacts

+923332902703, +923362105572. Climate Change forecasting through Timeseries Algorithms RNN and Linear Regression | Product Module | Co-Founder, Main Developer | Python | 10 January 2020 – 22 January 2020 | Agritech (Own) | Karachi

Based on Climate Change data analysis and forecast with Time Series Algorithms it's a part of my startup project.

Al deep learning-based OCR with scheduler | WPF app | Developer | C# | 1 November 2020 – 15 November 2020 | for client | Germany

Al based Optical Character recognition for both
Digital and handwritten text images and assignment
reminder

Pest Detection and Fruits Category and Quality
Detector through Deep Learning CNN | Product
Module | Co-Founder, Main Developer | Python | 11
December 2019 – 22 December 2019 | Agritech
(Own) | Karachi

Fruits Category and Quality Detector is a software application which helps to detect fruits type and quality in set of fruits by taking real time image as input, Convolutional Neural network it's a part of my startup project.

Bank Data Analysis with Genetic Algorithm
Optimized Hybrid Ensemble Learning Model |
Research Project | Computer Programmer | Python
| Jan 2018 – Nov 2019 | Jiangsu University of
Science and Technology | China

based on Genetic Algorithm based optimized combination of ensemble learning models to analyze the Banks client's data for Loan Marketing. I was working with Phd student Usman Ashraf Khan Jadoon at Zhengzhou University, China.

Comparison of Multi Linear regression, K nearest
Neighbor and neural network for House price
prediction | Research Project | Data Scientist &
Developer | R and python both | 1 March 2019 – 10
March 2019 | Youngston State University | USA

Based House price feature analysis for prediction with data analysis processes with ML models Multi linear regression, knn and neural network and compare the performance of the both predictions. I was working with MS Statistics student Qurat ulaian Sharif at Youngston State University of USA. And Phd Student Muhammad Suhaib at IIC University of Technology Japan

## IOT RESEARCH PROJECTS

Weather Stations for Farms | Product | Co-Founder, Main Developer | IoT | 10 Nov 2019 – Present | Agritech (Own) | Karachi

It's for My startup with Mr. Rashid Mehmood Bhatti the Founder of My Farm Basket, smart farming products, for live weather and soil quality forecasting for farmers

Autonomous Navigation Algorithm for Zumo 32U4 Robot | Computer Programmer | Ardunio, MatLab | Mar 2018 | Private | Karachi

this algorithm demonstrates algorithms to achieve tasks such as 'move to a point', 'move to a pose', 'follow a line', 'move in a circle' and 'avoid obstacles'. These control algorithms are simulated using Simulink models. I was with Areeba Saddique MS student at EE department NED University of Science and Technology

Call notifier LCD module via Bluetooth Autonomous Navigation Algorithm for Zumo 32U4 Robot | Computer Programmer | Arduino, Android | Mar 2018 | Private | Karachi

Hardware module with LCD and Bluetooth with Arduino circuit to receive call notification via Bluetooth from Android Phone Application.

### WEB, MOBILE & DESKTOP PROJECTS

Online Shopping | client Project |
Project Head Computer Programmer |
react,php,flutter & mysql | Nov 2018 |
Alphatron Technologies | Karachi
Online shopping web &mobile
application

My Farm Basket | client Project |
Project Head Computer Programmer |

### Twitter Sentiment Analysis | Research Project | Data Scientist & Developer | R | 1 March 2019 – 10 March 2019 | Deakin University | USA

Based on Twitter handles and Sentiment analysis of Play station with data science techniques and network graphs. I was working with student Zeeshan Ali at Deakin University of Australia.

### Speech Emotion and Language Disorder Analysis and Recognition | Research Project | Computer Programmer | Mat Lab | Oct 2016 - May 2017 | NED University | Karachi

SELDAR is a software application which helps to the people in research about the speech behavior of normal and special children's and recognize the state of language and the emotion and it's also calculate and record 12 features of speech and Sound, classify through Machine learning Hybrid Algorithm of Support Vector model(SVM), K Nearest Neighbor Model (KNN), Neural Networks (NN) and Dynamic Time Wrapping (DTW) and Deep Machine Learning CNN and SAE Neutral Network and show analysis recognition in category and emotion with percentage of matching and performance and error rate by table and graph comparison with other models. I worked with Dr Maria Siddique the Lecturer & PhD Student at SE department NED university.

### Environmental Sound Recognition By K nearest Neighbor Model of ML | Research Project | Computer Programmer | MATLAB | Jan 2018 -March 2018 | Jiangsu University of Science and Technology | China

ESR is a software application which helps to the people in research about the Environmental sounds of 49 different objects and recognize and it's also calculate and record 5 features of sound, classify through Machine learning K Nearest Neighbor Model (KNN) and show analysis recognition in category with percentage of matching and performance and error rate by table and graph comparison with other models 25 features of sound has been extracted and studied. I worked Komal Nerajo MS Student at Jiangsu university of Science and Technology in China.

# E Voting System Through Iris Recognition | Final Year Project | Group Leader Main Programmer | C# Asp.net, Mat Lab, SQL | June 2013 - Aug 2014 | UIT | Karachi

E-Voting System is a computerized voting system used in election process of any country,

asp.net | Nov 2018 | Alphatron Technologies | Karachi Online Organic Food and fruits ecommerce website

### Triplona | client Project | Project Head Computer Programmer | React Node.js | Nov 2018 | Alphatron Technologies | Karachi

Hotel Booking System with recommendation system, price prediction and optimized searching algorithm.

### Management Systems | Individual Project | Oct 2010 - Aug 2014 | UIT | Karachi

Car Selection & Dealership-C# AND ACCESS 2007

Loan Arranger- C# AND SQL Subway -C# AND ACCESS 2007

### Web Projects | Freelance Project | Feb 2015 - Aug 2016 | Iridium IT | Karachi

KANVA's Event Management Website - PHP,HTML5,CSS3,JS,JQUERY

Museum Website- PHP,HTML,CSS,JS Historical Places Website -PHP,HTML,CSS,JS

Music Mania-PHP, HTML, CSS, JS

### Desktop Projects | Freelance Project | Oct 2010 - Aug 2014 | Iridium IT | Karachi

String Searching Algorithms -C#
Numerology and Astronomy -C++
Binary /Quicksort Searching DEMO Java

Desktop Games-C#

### Mobile Projects | Freelance Project | Oct 2010 - Aug 2014 | Iridium IT | Karachi

I Smart Banking Demo- Android Student Attendance application -Android

### Format Preserving Encryption Algorithms | Research Project | Computer Programmer | C++ | Nov 2018 | - | Karachi

FF1 and FF3 algorithms with scholar and student from a university.

organization, society or event etc. We developed that E-voting system on ASP.NET which was integrated Iris recognition technique developed on MATLAB, distributed databases with both voter and election administration panel.

### Sea Surge Sensor based Data Analysis by Neural Networks | Research Project | Computer Programmer | MatLab | July 2018 | UIT | Karachi

6 sensor reading data analysis of real time sea data assist the project for Engr Talha Khan Assist Professor at Usman Institute of Technology.

### Game Player Agent by Reinforcement Learning's Q learning and TD Learning Algorithms | Research Project | Computer Programmer | Python | Deakin University | Sept 2018 | - | Karachi

with Q Learning Algorithm and Temporal Difference Algorithm for game agent control I worked with Muhammad Hassan student of Deakin University, Austrailia.

Game Player Agent by Maximizer Minimizer
Algorithm | Research Project | Computer
Programmer | Python | Deakin University | Sept
2018 | - | Karachi

Applied on 2 player nim game for client.

Neural Network Weight Training by Genetic Algorithm | Research Project | Computer Programmer | Python | Sept 2018 | - | Karachi

Application of different types or my previous neural Network project for a client.

I-Interpreter (Deaf/Dumb Speech Interpreter) | Research Project | | Computer Programmer | C# Windows Platform, A Forge, Android | Aug 2015 -Nov 2015 | Private | Karachi

I-Interpreter is a software application which helps the people with hearing and speaking disorder to communicate with others in include speech recognition and sign gestures recognition (image processing through OPEN CV) technique integrated with windows and android application. Working with HOD of SE Dr Najami, Professor Dr Abbas and Lecturer & PhD student Maria Siddique of NED university.

### Particle Swarm Optimization | Research Project | Computer Programmer | C# Windows Platform | Mar 2015 - May 2015 | Private | Karachi

PSO is related with Swarm intelligence which is modern Artificial Intelligence discipline that is concerned with design of multi agent systems. I'm working on human speech sample with Senior

### Playfair Cipher | academic Project | Computer Programmer | C# | Nov 2012 | - | Karachi

Text to Playfair Encryption by Key.

Researcher Maria Siddique who is the PHD Student at NED University. This algorithm was implemented for clustering sample of multiple speech features.		